# Will Tisdale

Software Developer

334-328-9186

will.tisdale.31@gmail.com LinkedIn: in/WillTisdale/

GitHub: /WillTisdale

Operations management professional with a passion for software development. 10 years with the United Parcel Service has created an increased appreciation for process improvement and how implementing new technologies can assist. Transitioning into software development with the goal of developing software that improves the client and customer experience.

### Technical Skills

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

BootStrap

VCS with Git

Paired Programming

Thymeleaf

Test-Driven Development

Java SE

MySQL

Spring Boot Framework

jQuery

**Object-Oriented Programming** 

Java EE (Servlets, JSP)

### Development Projects

#### **Coffee Project**

This project uses JavaScript to dynamically update the HTML of a webpage. Uses the functionality of sorting, adding, and removing elements from the page.

### **Weather Map**

Uses HTML, CSS, jQuery, AJAX, and the OpenWeatherMap API to dynamically update the current weather conditions based on the users input for location.

### **Ad Lister**

Uses Java and the MVC design pattern for a fully functioning site where users can create an account, login, post and update ads, as well as search through all existing ads.

### Professional Experience

### United Parcel Service - San Antonio, TX Aug. 2019 - Jul. 2020

On Road Supervisor

- Successfully trained drivers on industry leading safe driving methods in order to achieve world class results in safety.
- Provided annual safety training for existing drivers and new driver training.
- HAZMAT certified responsible for handling leaking or damaged HAZMAT packages in the facility or on the road.

## United Parcel Service - Virginia Beach, VA Jul. 2017 - Aug. 2019 Dispatcher

- Implemented plans and managed operations on Saturdays to compete with other delivery companies for the first time in the companies history.
- Used software to develop plans for all routes regarding over 6,000 delivery stops, 20,000 packages, and 1,000 pickup stops pr day in order to increase efficiency and reduce cost.

### United Parcel Service - Montgomery, AL Nov. 2012 - Jul. 2017 Dispatcher

• Streamlined the process for operations involving loading delivery trucks with respect to package counts as well as employee efficiency.

### Education

### Codeup 2021

Certificate of Completion

A fully-immersive, project-based, and intensive 22-week full-stack Java career accelerator that provides students with 670+ hours of expert instruction in software development.

### Troy University 2016

Associate of Science in General Education